<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devops on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/categories/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devops on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 11:18:06 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://calgaryrhce.ca/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Automation Controller API with OAUTH</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-10-10-oauth-controller-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 11:18:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-10-10-oauth-controller-api/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to spend some time outlining how to query the Automation Controller API using OAUTH tokens. A few customers have reached out with these questions and I noticed the documentation on it doesn&amp;rsquo;t immediately suggest the answer. So it&amp;rsquo;s time for a Solution Architect to step in! These are the common questions we&amp;rsquo;ll answer in this post:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Automation Metrics</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-automation-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:28:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-automation-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Another topic that&amp;rsquo;s come up a lot over the past year or more has been around metrics. I&amp;rsquo;m sure by now you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of the Four Keys developed by Google. Now, these metrics get a lot of coverage in the spotlight, but should everyone use them? Not everyone is at Google&amp;rsquo;s level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduating with Automation Practices</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-graduating-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:20:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-graduating-automation/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in a lot of automation discussions. Particularly around governance, standards, scale, workflows, best practices, and the list goes on. My impression is that folks are looking at establishing some of the common foundations to an automation practice and are getting farther down their DevOps &amp;amp; Automation journeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Automation Platform Notifications for package reporting</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-10-26-aap-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 13:18:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-10-26-aap-notifications/</guid>
      <description>I was recently asked to outline the options available to do package reporting after a patch cycle for RHEL. There was preference to try to do this in Ansible Automation Platform, consumed via an emailed report, so I&amp;rsquo;ll focus the bulk of the effort there. The specifics were to have view into what packages were installed, updated, removed, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Autonomous Containerized Deployment, part 2</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-07-07-fully-autonomous-containerized-deployment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 05:36:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-07-07-fully-autonomous-containerized-deployment-2/</guid>
      <description>Building upon the previous article, let&amp;rsquo;s review what we&amp;rsquo;ve built so far:
Deployed a self-managing container OS based on Fedora CoreOS Configured Fedora CoreOS to automatically update itself Setup intelligent health checks and automated rollbacks for any failed updates I&amp;rsquo;m going to tackle this first from an upstream approach with Fedora CoreOS, however there&amp;rsquo;s an excellent article written on this same topic for RHEL for Edge by Brian Smith that covers this incredibly well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Autonomous Containerized Deployment, part 1</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-07-07-fully-autonomous-containerized-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 11:36:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-07-07-fully-autonomous-containerized-deployment/</guid>
      <description>After a pandemic hiatus, I&amp;rsquo;m back with some renewed vigor to blogging. Over the past two years, I&amp;rsquo;ve built up several topics that have been stuck in my head and need to get put down to (digital) paper. I think I&amp;rsquo;m finally at a spot with either spare sanity or needing a purposeful distraction that keeps me from doomscrolling the news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Fedora Atomic to Fedora CoreOS</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2020/02/24/moving-from-fedora-atomic-to-fedora-coreos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 23:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2020/02/24/moving-from-fedora-atomic-to-fedora-coreos/</guid>
      <description>Recently the merging of Fedora Atomic and CoreOS Container Linux into what is now known as Fedora CoreOS has moved out of preview and is ready for prime time use. I’ve been running a few small container apps on a Fedora Atomic 28 VM, which is now ripe to be moved into the new replacement Fedora CoreOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD with Ansible Tower and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/ci-cd-with-ansible-tower-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/ci-cd-with-ansible-tower-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Every so often I come across an interesting use-case or a really creative way to integrate different technology that I haven’t seen before. I follow a few folks on social media and blogs that do this stuff on a regular basis, one of them being Keith Tenzer. He’s put together a really interesting demo of Ansible Tower connected with GitHub and a webhook that showcases how CI/CD can be accomplished using Ansible without the need for a formal CI/CD pipeline toolset like Jenkins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat Insights – a predictive analytics engine in RHEL</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/red-hat-insights-a-predictive-analytics-engine-in-rhel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/red-hat-insights-a-predictive-analytics-engine-in-rhel/</guid>
      <description>Something Engineering has been working hard on over the past couple of years is connecting Red Hat’s wealth of internal knowledge with items and issues customers face in the real world everyday. Born out of this effort was Red Hat Insights, a predictive analytics engine that analyzes, assesses, and builds automation to remediate issues found in customer environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating custom credentials in Ansible Tower</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/creating-custom-credentials-in-ansible-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 22:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/creating-custom-credentials-in-ansible-tower/</guid>
      <description>As we go further in our efforts to automate all the things with ansible, you will likely come across a need to manage some cusom credentials that do not come with a predefined type in Ansible Tower. You might be currently setting these in an environment variable, in group_vars or host_vars, or perhaps hardcoded into a playbook itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding python virtual environments (venvs) to Ansible Tower</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/adding-python-virtual-environments-venvs-to-ansible-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 18:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/adding-python-virtual-environments-venvs-to-ansible-tower/</guid>
      <description>As you’re developing playbooks you may find that you need to add additional python capability in order to use some modules. These are easy enough to install on a regular linux client with pip, but how does this work for Ansible Tower? Fortunately this is not too different for Ansible Tower, we’re just going to instruct Tower to add another source directory for our new venvs, and then assign these in Tower at an Organization, Project, or Job Template level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limiting Ansible Tower inventory with Satellite host groups</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/06/13/limiting-ansible-tower-inventory-with-satellite-host-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 15:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/06/13/limiting-ansible-tower-inventory-with-satellite-host-groups/</guid>
      <description>When thinking about ingesting systems into Ansible Tower’s inventory, a common use-case is to intelligently filter hosts into Ansible Tower such that we’re selectively adding only the hosts we want into Tower inventory. When pairing with Red Hat Satellite, we can use Satellite’s host grouping feature combined with Ansible Tower’s Satellite 6 dynamic inventory script to apply this filtering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Ansible Tower to Team Foundation Server</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/06/connecting-ansible-tower-to-team-foundation-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 18:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/06/connecting-ansible-tower-to-team-foundation-server/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was investigating how to connect Ansible Tower to Microsoft Team Foundation Server to source a git repo. To document this for later, I discovered that the way to do this is with an SSH key, and by turning on the SSH service on TFS. Here’s how I got it working:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Workshop Materials</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/02/28/ansible-workshop-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/02/28/ansible-workshop-materials/</guid>
      <description>Recently we had one of the largest and most interesting meetups I think the Calgary market has seen in quite a while. We were able to run an Ansible Workshop, which is a mix of presentation and hands-on lab content. What makes these workshops different (and a reason people love them) is we get to teach a concept, then implement it in a lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Azure VM with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/01/03/create-azure-vm-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/01/03/create-azure-vm-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>With a little googling this task isn’t very complex, however, for those wanting to consume this information easily – this post is for you.
There’s a lot of cloud provisioning tools out there; if you’re like me and prefer to leverage your existing knowledge wherever possible you might come to the conclusion that using the same tool to provision your VMs as you do to manage them makes sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCI-DSS Compliance with Ansible Tower</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/01/02/pci-dss-compliance-with-ansible-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 17:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/01/02/pci-dss-compliance-with-ansible-tower/</guid>
      <description>Compliance scanning and remediation with Ansible is a common question that comes up. How does Ansible do this? What are its capabilities? Within the Ansible Galaxy community, there’s been some significant investment in developing ansible roles for security and compliance. I’ll show you how to download this Ansible role and make use of it within Ansible Tower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ansible to manage RHV/oVirt</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/using-ansible-to-manage-rhv-ovirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 21:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/using-ansible-to-manage-rhv-ovirt/</guid>
      <description>A common task most virtualization administrators will perform is installing the guest agent(s) among their guest VMs. Ansible has a nice module that allows an administrator to automate these common tasks, such as attaching/detaching a CDROM device to a VM, rebooting several VMs, etc. Combining this with ansible’s management of Windows devices and it makes it fairly trivial to automate a mass installation of guest agents in windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most performance out of Openstack, and NFV</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/10/14/getting-the-most-performance-out-of-openstack-and-nfv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 17:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/10/14/getting-the-most-performance-out-of-openstack-and-nfv/</guid>
      <description>By now, most IT staff has either had a chance to deploy OpenStack, or at least are familiar with what it is and what benefits it offers. We’ve moved past the installer race, the fragmentation of “as-a-service” components, and endless TCO calculators. The ecosystem and community has reached a maturity stage where the media and industry alike are calling OpenStack “boring“.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calgary OpenStack and other Meetup.com groups</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/03/21/calgary-openstack-and-other-meetup-com-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 23:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/03/21/calgary-openstack-and-other-meetup-com-groups/</guid>
      <description>I’m a little late on this post, but last week we had an excellent presentation on OpenStack installers. Specifically, TripleO. Chris J from Red Hat gave us a good outline of TripleO’s capabilities, and kept it pretty upstream. For the presentation slide deck, see here. The group tries to keep it as vendor neutral as possible which is nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing OpenStack installers</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/10/comparing-openstack-installers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 22:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/10/comparing-openstack-installers/</guid>
      <description>Building on a previous post, I promised I’d do a comparison of open source OpenStack installers. Choosing an installer requires more thought than most people think, as the choices are vast, and each installer offers different strengths, benefits, and trade-offs. Depending on your environment’s purpose and intended result, it would be wise to align your needs with the installers’ capabilities and limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/08/21/getting-started-with-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 01:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/08/21/getting-started-with-openstack/</guid>
      <description>So you’d like to get started with OpenStack eh? (Sorry, that’s my Canadian coming through). You may have been thinking about it for a while, evaluating the landscape, the maturity, evaluating your tolerance for new technology, and waiting for the right time to adopt. Being on the verge of adopting a new and disruptive technology is an intimidating place to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible-pull and kickstart, for one-touch server provisioning</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/02/03/ansible-pull-and-kickstart-for-one-touch-server-provisioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 20:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/02/03/ansible-pull-and-kickstart-for-one-touch-server-provisioning/</guid>
      <description>Recently I’ve been learning and using Ansible as my configuration management tool. It came recommended by several colleagues, recently had an O’Reilly book published, and went through an aquisition. Safe to say its momentum and adoption is on a high… and so far, I’m loving using it. I find it vastly easier to setup and use than Puppet, Chef, CFengine, or SaltStack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Server Provisioning; the Transition to Private Hybrid Cloud</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 23:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</guid>
      <description>In every place I’ve worked, the server provisioning process was largely identical. There were of course subtle differences depending on vendor products, business processes, etc. but typically every customer’s server provisioning artifacts are made up of the same components. To provision a host, you’ll need IP information, DNS entry, VM container, a kickstart/jumpstart method, pre-provisioned storage/networks, and all of the various application level components on top of the OS (monitoring agents, backups, the application itself, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying automation and Puppet</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/demystifying-automation-and-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/demystifying-automation-and-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Automation has grown from its traditional roots of simple scripting into a critical cog of present day IT infrastructure. Today we have full fledged software suites based on automation. We have myriads of start-ups who base their entire business model on it. Every CIO is including it in their execution strategy, and you can’t seem to find a conference that doesn’t have a trendy buzzword filled keynote dedicated to the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Configuration Management w/ Puppet</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/11/23/managing-configuration-management-w-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 21:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/11/23/managing-configuration-management-w-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of the past year or so, Puppet has taken off in popularity amongst developers and administrators. It’s becoming the de-facto tool for repeatable state and drift management, and part of the reason for the uptake in popularity of the DevOps culture. As with most techology that grows quickly and organically, it often looks much different a year into implementation than it did day one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliable, resilient storage with GlusterFS</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/08/18/reliable-resilient-storage-with-glusterfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 05:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/08/18/reliable-resilient-storage-with-glusterfs/</guid>
      <description>A need came up lately for some inexpensive resilient storage that was easily expandable, and that spanned multiple datacentres. Having recently been playing with GlusterFS and Swift in our OpenStack trial, I was quick to point out that these were strong use-cases for a GlusterFS architecture. We needed something right away, and something that also wasn’t terribly expensive, which Gluster caters to quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating kickstart w/ CentOS 6 DVD ISO installation</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/06/21/integrating-kickstart-w-centos-6-dvd-iso-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 20:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/06/21/integrating-kickstart-w-centos-6-dvd-iso-installation/</guid>
      <description>In our DevOps environment, we’ve got a lot of developers who regularly build VMs. Sometimes they’re built locally on their workstations, or sometimes in the data center when they’re ready to formally move code. Admittedly, the IT VM provisioning process can be slow at times and we often see them get frustrated and take matters into their own hands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
