<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux kernel on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/linux-kernel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux kernel on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 16:17:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/linux-kernel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>32-bit application support in RHEL7</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/07/32-bit-application-support-in-rhel7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/07/32-bit-application-support-in-rhel7/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to check the supportability of 32-bit applications in Red Hat Enterprise Linux. RHEL can support 32-bit applications in a 64-bit environment in the following scenarios:
 https://access.redhat.com/solutions/509373  Additionally, with the multilib toolchain, one can install the 32-bit packages by specifying the architecture in the yum install command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting performance of VDO and NFS</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/20/troubleshooting-performance-of-vdo-and-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 17:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/20/troubleshooting-performance-of-vdo-and-nfs/</guid>
      <description>In setting up a local virtualization environment a little while back, I thought I&amp;#8217;d try the recently GA&amp;#8217;d VDO capabilities in the RHEL 7.5 kernel. These include data compression and de-duplication natively in the linux kernel (through a kernel module). This was Red Hat&amp;#8217;s efforts behind the Permabit acquisition. Considering a virtualization data store is a prime candidate for a de-duplication use-case, I was anxious to reclaim some of my storage budget 🙂 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading from Fedora 23 to Fedora 24</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/10/15/upgrading-from-fedora-23-to-fedora-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 20:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/10/15/upgrading-from-fedora-23-to-fedora-24/</guid>
      <description>For my main workstation, I&amp;#8217;ve been running linux for about 8 or 9 years now and specifically Fedora for the past 3. I&amp;#8217;ve tried to keep my workstation kernel around about the same version as the systems I maintain in the datacentre, typically just slightly ahead. This helps relate my workstation experience to the datacentre, and also keeps me slightly ahead of the learning curve getting experience with the new tools that come in, or figuring out workarounds prior to needing to do them in production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How open source strikes the right balance between social and market norms</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/01/07/how-open-source-strikes-the-right-balance-between-social-and-market-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 20:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/01/07/how-open-source-strikes-the-right-balance-between-social-and-market-norms/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;#8217;ve been knocking off a few books that have accumulated on my &amp;#8220;must-read&amp;#8221; list. One of my favourites came recommended by my technical sales professor at SAIT, &amp;#8220;Predictably Irrational, by Dan Ariely. It&amp;#8217;s a New York Times bestseller. It was recommended based on its insights around behavioural science, specifically what factors influence a buyer&amp;#8217;s decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>