<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social motivation on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/social-motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social motivation on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 20:54:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/social-motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How open source strikes the right balance between social and market norms</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/01/07/how-open-source-strikes-the-right-balance-between-social-and-market-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 20:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/01/07/how-open-source-strikes-the-right-balance-between-social-and-market-norms/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I’ve been knocking off a few books that have accumulated on my “must-read” list. One of my favourites came recommended by my technical sales professor at SAIT, “Predictably Irrational, by Dan Ariely. It’s a New York Times bestseller. It was recommended based on its insights around behavioural science, specifically what factors influence a buyer’s decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Employees and Strategies of Influence</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/11/29/motivating-employees-and-strategies-of-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 22:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/11/29/motivating-employees-and-strategies-of-influence/</guid>
      <description>I know, I know. Another management topic. Haven’t we heard enough leadership buzzwords? Seen enough trendy motivational topics? Like probably most of you, I dread the elevator pitch of anyone about to give me a spiel on the latest and greatest industry buzzword topic. Especially if all they did was read an article on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation – Autonomy, Mastery, Purpose; &amp; The Open Organization</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/08/09/motivation-autonomy-mastery-purpose-the-open-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 19:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/08/09/motivation-autonomy-mastery-purpose-the-open-organization/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been paying attention to the open source community lately, or are keen to keeping abreast of the latest trends in corporate leadership or management, you may have heard of Jim Whitehurst’s new book titled The Open Organization. The book compares and contrasts leadership styles and engagement strategies in the modern corporate world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
