<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kickstart on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://aludwar.github.io/tags/kickstart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kickstart on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 20:55:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aludwar.github.io/tags/kickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible-pull and kickstart, for one-touch server provisioning</title>
      <link>https://aludwar.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/ansible-pull-and-kickstart-for-one-touch-server-provisioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 20:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aludwar.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/ansible-pull-and-kickstart-for-one-touch-server-provisioning/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;#8217;ve been learning and using Ansible as my configuration management tool. It came recommended by several colleagues, recently had an O&amp;#8217;Reilly book published, and went through an aquisition. Safe to say its momentum and adoption is on a high&amp;#8230; and so far, I&amp;#8217;m loving using it. I find it vastly easier to setup and use than Puppet, Chef, CFengine, or SaltStack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Server Provisioning; the Transition to Private Hybrid Cloud</title>
      <link>https://aludwar.github.io/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 23:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aludwar.github.io/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</guid>
      <description>In every place I&amp;#8217;ve worked, the server provisioning process was largely identical. There were of course subtle differences depending on vendor products, business processes, etc. but typically every customer&amp;#8217;s server provisioning artifacts are made up of the same components. To provision a host, you&amp;#8217;ll need IP information, DNS entry, VM container, a kickstart/jumpstart method, pre-provisioned storage/networks, and all of the various application level components on top of the OS (monitoring agents, backups, the application itself, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating kickstart w/ CentOS 6 DVD ISO installation</title>
      <link>https://aludwar.github.io/blog/2014/06/21/integrating-kickstart-w-centos-6-dvd-iso-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 20:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aludwar.github.io/blog/2014/06/21/integrating-kickstart-w-centos-6-dvd-iso-installation/</guid>
      <description>In our DevOps environment, we&amp;#8217;ve got a lot of developers who regularly build VMs. Sometimes they&amp;#8217;re built locally on their workstations, or sometimes in the data center when they&amp;#8217;re ready to formally move code. Admittedly, the IT VM provisioning process can be slow at times and we often see them get frustrated and take matters into their own hands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>