<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>enterprise on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/categories/enterprise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in enterprise on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 16:08:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://calgaryrhce.ca/categories/enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enabling nested virtualization with RHV 4.3</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/11/08/enabling-nested-virtualization-with-rhv-4-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 16:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/11/08/enabling-nested-virtualization-with-rhv-4-3/</guid>
      <description>To enable nested virtualization within a Red Hat Virtualization 4.3 environment, you will need to do two things. First, make sure the “vdsm-hook-nestedvt” package is present on the host hypervisor. You’ll need to restart vdsmd as well after installing.
Second, you’ll need to enable the Pass-Through Host CPU option in the virtual machine settings (under the host section).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32-bit application support in RHEL7</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/07/32-bit-application-support-in-rhel7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/07/32-bit-application-support-in-rhel7/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to check the supportability of 32-bit applications in Red Hat Enterprise Linux. RHEL can support 32-bit applications in a 64-bit environment in the following scenarios:
https://access.redhat.com/solutions/509373 Additionally, with the multilib toolchain, one can install the 32-bit packages by specifying the architecture in the yum install command:
# yum install glibc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Workshop Materials</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/02/28/ansible-workshop-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/02/28/ansible-workshop-materials/</guid>
      <description>Recently we had one of the largest and most interesting meetups I think the Calgary market has seen in quite a while. We were able to run an Ansible Workshop, which is a mix of presentation and hands-on lab content. What makes these workshops different (and a reason people love them) is we get to teach a concept, then implement it in a lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing VMs into RHV from KVM</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/importing-vms-into-rhv-from-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 16:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/importing-vms-into-rhv-from-kvm/</guid>
      <description>To import virtual machines from a KVM/libvirt hypervisor into Red Hat Virtualization, is pretty easy. RHV will handle the v2v copying for you in the background, there are just a couple prerequisite steps to take prior to importing. On the RHV hypervisor host you’re proxying the import connection through, setup passwordless SSH from the vdsm user to the root user on the source hypervisor:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting performance of VDO and NFS</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/20/troubleshooting-performance-of-vdo-and-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 17:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/20/troubleshooting-performance-of-vdo-and-nfs/</guid>
      <description>In setting up a local virtualization environment a little while back, I thought I’d try the recently GA’d VDO capabilities in the RHEL 7.5 kernel. These include data compression and de-duplication natively in the linux kernel (through a kernel module). This was Red Hat’s efforts behind the Permabit acquisition. Considering a virtualization data store is a prime candidate for a de-duplication use-case, I was anxious to reclaim some of my storage budget 🙂 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calgary OpenStack and other Meetup.com groups</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/03/21/calgary-openstack-and-other-meetup-com-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 23:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/03/21/calgary-openstack-and-other-meetup-com-groups/</guid>
      <description>I’m a little late on this post, but last week we had an excellent presentation on OpenStack installers. Specifically, TripleO. Chris J from Red Hat gave us a good outline of TripleO’s capabilities, and kept it pretty upstream. For the presentation slide deck, see here. The group tries to keep it as vendor neutral as possible which is nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network teaming in RHEL7</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/11/24/network-teaming-in-rhel7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 22:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/11/24/network-teaming-in-rhel7/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve adopted or are just starting to read up on the new features included in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7, you may have come across the new networking feature called teaming. It essentially is a replacement for bonding that offers more modularity, increased link monitoring features, higher network performance, and easier management of interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home lab switch replacement</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/10/30/home-lab-switch-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 23:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/10/30/home-lab-switch-replacement/</guid>
      <description>A few years back, I purged nearly all of my computer components that were kicking around the house, thus essentially abandoning my home lab. I had learned what I needed to with it, and had enough equipment at work to get done what I needed, so off it went. Old PCs, switches, cables, parts, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Employees and Strategies of Influence</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/11/29/motivating-employees-and-strategies-of-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 22:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/11/29/motivating-employees-and-strategies-of-influence/</guid>
      <description>I know, I know. Another management topic. Haven’t we heard enough leadership buzzwords? Seen enough trendy motivational topics? Like probably most of you, I dread the elevator pitch of anyone about to give me a spiel on the latest and greatest industry buzzword topic. Especially if all they did was read an article on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Server Provisioning; the Transition to Private Hybrid Cloud</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 23:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</guid>
      <description>In every place I’ve worked, the server provisioning process was largely identical. There were of course subtle differences depending on vendor products, business processes, etc. but typically every customer’s server provisioning artifacts are made up of the same components. To provision a host, you’ll need IP information, DNS entry, VM container, a kickstart/jumpstart method, pre-provisioned storage/networks, and all of the various application level components on top of the OS (monitoring agents, backups, the application itself, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying automation and Puppet</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/demystifying-automation-and-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/demystifying-automation-and-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Automation has grown from its traditional roots of simple scripting into a critical cog of present day IT infrastructure. Today we have full fledged software suites based on automation. We have myriads of start-ups who base their entire business model on it. Every CIO is including it in their execution strategy, and you can’t seem to find a conference that doesn’t have a trendy buzzword filled keynote dedicated to the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Foundation – Guide to the Open Cloud</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/02/18/the-linux-foundation-guide-to-the-open-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 02:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/02/18/the-linux-foundation-guide-to-the-open-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Never before has the IT industry faced such a colossal rate of change and innovation as it does today. The pace is even more prominent in emerging technologies such as big data, the internet of things, and cloud computing. At the heart of all of these trends is open source. Open source has enabled both the mass collaboration and massive scaling that is driving cloud technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aggregation w/ LACP</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/09/15/link-aggregation-w-lacp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 19:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/09/15/link-aggregation-w-lacp/</guid>
      <description>Link aggregation is not a new concept, yet I still see a lot of folks who don’t make regular use of it. With regard to server networking architecture, especially in heavily virtualized or highly available environments, it’s a crucial tool that provides redundancy, and slightly increased throughput. For how simple it is to implement, it is a no-brainer to consider for physical server networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliable, resilient storage with GlusterFS</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/08/18/reliable-resilient-storage-with-glusterfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 05:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/08/18/reliable-resilient-storage-with-glusterfs/</guid>
      <description>A need came up lately for some inexpensive resilient storage that was easily expandable, and that spanned multiple datacentres. Having recently been playing with GlusterFS and Swift in our OpenStack trial, I was quick to point out that these were strong use-cases for a GlusterFS architecture. We needed something right away, and something that also wasn’t terribly expensive, which Gluster caters to quite well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective communication</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/06/19/effective-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 04:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2014/06/19/effective-communication/</guid>
      <description>As an IT professional, one of the most important job skills you can possess may not necessarily be technical. Excuse me, what? How is that so? We’re IT people! If we’re masters of anything, it’s the technical bits in the trade!
Typical studies show that we spend 70-80% of our day communicating with others, and 40% of our day interacting with others’ writing (source, source).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
