<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automation on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automation on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:28:04 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Automation Metrics</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-automation-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:28:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-automation-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Another topic that&amp;rsquo;s come up a lot over the past year or more has been around metrics. I&amp;rsquo;m sure by now you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of the Four Keys developed by Google. Now, these metrics get a lot of coverage in the spotlight, but should everyone use them? Not everyone is at Google&amp;rsquo;s level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduating with Automation Practices</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-graduating-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:20:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-graduating-automation/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in a lot of automation discussions. Particularly around governance, standards, scale, workflows, best practices, and the list goes on. My impression is that folks are looking at establishing some of the common foundations to an automation practice and are getting farther down their DevOps &amp;amp; Automation journeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Automation Platform Notifications for package reporting</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-10-26-aap-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 13:18:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-10-26-aap-notifications/</guid>
      <description>I was recently asked to outline the options available to do package reporting after a patch cycle for RHEL. There was preference to try to do this in Ansible Automation Platform, consumed via an emailed report, so I&amp;rsquo;ll focus the bulk of the effort there. The specifics were to have view into what packages were installed, updated, removed, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat Insights – a predictive analytics engine in RHEL</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/red-hat-insights-a-predictive-analytics-engine-in-rhel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/red-hat-insights-a-predictive-analytics-engine-in-rhel/</guid>
      <description>Something Engineering has been working hard on over the past couple of years is connecting Red Hat’s wealth of internal knowledge with items and issues customers face in the real world everyday. Born out of this effort was Red Hat Insights, a predictive analytics engine that analyzes, assesses, and builds automation to remediate issues found in customer environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying automation and Puppet</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/demystifying-automation-and-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/demystifying-automation-and-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Automation has grown from its traditional roots of simple scripting into a critical cog of present day IT infrastructure. Today we have full fledged software suites based on automation. We have myriads of start-ups who base their entire business model on it. Every CIO is including it in their execution strategy, and you can’t seem to find a conference that doesn’t have a trendy buzzword filled keynote dedicated to the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
