<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>private cloud on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/private-cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in private cloud on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 21:09:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/private-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using ansible to manage RHV/oVirt</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/using-ansible-to-manage-rhv-ovirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 21:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/using-ansible-to-manage-rhv-ovirt/</guid>
      <description>A common task most virtualization administrators will perform is installing the guest agent(s) among their guest VMs. Ansible has a nice module that allows an administrator to automate these common tasks, such as attaching/detaching a CDROM device to a VM, rebooting several VMs, etc. Combining this with ansible’s management of Windows devices and it makes it fairly trivial to automate a mass installation of guest agents in windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing VMs into RHV from KVM</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/importing-vms-into-rhv-from-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 16:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/23/importing-vms-into-rhv-from-kvm/</guid>
      <description>To import virtual machines from a KVM/libvirt hypervisor into Red Hat Virtualization, is pretty easy. RHV will handle the v2v copying for you in the background, there are just a couple prerequisite steps to take prior to importing. On the RHV hypervisor host you’re proxying the import connection through, setup passwordless SSH from the vdsm user to the root user on the source hypervisor:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting performance of VDO and NFS</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/20/troubleshooting-performance-of-vdo-and-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 17:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/20/troubleshooting-performance-of-vdo-and-nfs/</guid>
      <description>In setting up a local virtualization environment a little while back, I thought I’d try the recently GA’d VDO capabilities in the RHEL 7.5 kernel. These include data compression and de-duplication natively in the linux kernel (through a kernel module). This was Red Hat’s efforts behind the Permabit acquisition. Considering a virtualization data store is a prime candidate for a de-duplication use-case, I was anxious to reclaim some of my storage budget 🙂 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating RHEV storage domains</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/19/migrating-rhev-storage-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 21:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2018/10/19/migrating-rhev-storage-domains/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I’ve been doing some troubleshooting in my virtualization environment, specifically with the NFS storage backing it. To isolate an issue I needed to migrate all the VM disks off the main data store to another one. I hadn’t performed this kind of activity before, but found it to be quite easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most performance out of Openstack, and NFV</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/10/14/getting-the-most-performance-out-of-openstack-and-nfv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 17:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/10/14/getting-the-most-performance-out-of-openstack-and-nfv/</guid>
      <description>By now, most IT staff has either had a chance to deploy OpenStack, or at least are familiar with what it is and what benefits it offers. We’ve moved past the installer race, the fragmentation of “as-a-service” components, and endless TCO calculators. The ecosystem and community has reached a maturity stage where the media and industry alike are calling OpenStack “boring“.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home lab, CAT6 wiring, and rack</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/09/13/home-lab-cat6-wiring-and-rack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 18:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/09/13/home-lab-cat6-wiring-and-rack/</guid>
      <description>Between being busy with home renovations, and writing articles for work, I haven’t made much time for blogging this summer. Since it’s raining today and hampering my home renos, I’m finally getting to a post on the work I did wiring my house with CAT 6, and setting up a home lab rack in the basement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calgary OpenStack and other Meetup.com groups</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/03/21/calgary-openstack-and-other-meetup-com-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 23:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2017/03/21/calgary-openstack-and-other-meetup-com-groups/</guid>
      <description>I’m a little late on this post, but last week we had an excellent presentation on OpenStack installers. Specifically, TripleO. Chris J from Red Hat gave us a good outline of TripleO’s capabilities, and kept it pretty upstream. For the presentation slide deck, see here. The group tries to keep it as vendor neutral as possible which is nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack deployment troubles? Enter a couple validation tools</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/10/27/openstack-deployment-troubles-enter-a-couple-validation-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/10/27/openstack-deployment-troubles-enter-a-couple-validation-tools/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re on your first or hundredth OpenStack deployment, any administrator will tell you that getting the initial deployment configuration correct is crucial. This gets easier with experience, but what can one do in the meantime to supplement that knowledge? Enter two tools: clapper, and the network isolation template generator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying an OpenStack cluster in a virtual lab environment</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/24/deploying-an-openstack-cluster-in-a-virtual-lab-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 21:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/24/deploying-an-openstack-cluster-in-a-virtual-lab-environment/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I went through a couple OpenStack topics on installers, and deploying an undercloud as part of a virtual OpenStack deployment. Today I’ll walk through the overcloud deployment, and hopefully by the end of this post you will have had enough details to get your own deployment up and running. This particular environment is for Red Hat OpenStack Platform 8 (Liberty), but the same steps will apply to Mitaka as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OpenStack – setting up a virtual lab environment</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/11/installing-openstack-setting-up-a-virtual-lab-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 22:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/11/installing-openstack-setting-up-a-virtual-lab-environment/</guid>
      <description>When talking TripleO, there’s two concepts introduced called the “undercloud”, and the “overcloud”. These are essentially the labels for each OpenStack environment when referring to “OpenStack on OpenStack” (TripleO). The undercloud is the OpenStack server that manages and deploys the more publicly consumable overcloud servers that make up the OpenStack environment that we’re after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing OpenStack installers</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/10/comparing-openstack-installers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 22:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/10/comparing-openstack-installers/</guid>
      <description>Building on a previous post, I promised I’d do a comparison of open source OpenStack installers. Choosing an installer requires more thought than most people think, as the choices are vast, and each installer offers different strengths, benefits, and trade-offs. Depending on your environment’s purpose and intended result, it would be wise to align your needs with the installers’ capabilities and limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/08/21/getting-started-with-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 01:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/08/21/getting-started-with-openstack/</guid>
      <description>So you’d like to get started with OpenStack eh? (Sorry, that’s my Canadian coming through). You may have been thinking about it for a while, evaluating the landscape, the maturity, evaluating your tolerance for new technology, and waiting for the right time to adopt. Being on the verge of adopting a new and disruptive technology is an intimidating place to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Server Provisioning; the Transition to Private Hybrid Cloud</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 23:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2015/07/05/automating-server-provisioning-the-transition-to-private-hybrid-cloud/</guid>
      <description>In every place I’ve worked, the server provisioning process was largely identical. There were of course subtle differences depending on vendor products, business processes, etc. but typically every customer’s server provisioning artifacts are made up of the same components. To provision a host, you’ll need IP information, DNS entry, VM container, a kickstart/jumpstart method, pre-provisioned storage/networks, and all of the various application level components on top of the OS (monitoring agents, backups, the application itself, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
