<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ansible on Calgary RHCE</title>
    <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/ansible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ansible on Calgary RHCE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:20:21 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://calgaryrhce.ca/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Graduating with Automation Practices</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-graduating-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:20:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2023-09-21-graduating-automation/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been engaged in a lot of automation discussions. Particularly around governance, standards, scale, workflows, best practices, and the list goes on. My impression is that folks are looking at establishing some of the common foundations to an automation practice and are getting farther down their DevOps &amp;amp; Automation journeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Automation Platform Notifications for package reporting</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-10-26-aap-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 13:18:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/posts/2022-10-26-aap-notifications/</guid>
      <description>I was recently asked to outline the options available to do package reporting after a patch cycle for RHEL. There was preference to try to do this in Ansible Automation Platform, consumed via an emailed report, so I&amp;rsquo;ll focus the bulk of the effort there. The specifics were to have view into what packages were installed, updated, removed, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD with Ansible Tower and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/ci-cd-with-ansible-tower-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/ci-cd-with-ansible-tower-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Every so often I come across an interesting use-case or a really creative way to integrate different technology that I haven’t seen before. I follow a few folks on social media and blogs that do this stuff on a regular basis, one of them being Keith Tenzer. He’s put together a really interesting demo of Ansible Tower connected with GitHub and a webhook that showcases how CI/CD can be accomplished using Ansible without the need for a formal CI/CD pipeline toolset like Jenkins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat Insights – a predictive analytics engine in RHEL</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/red-hat-insights-a-predictive-analytics-engine-in-rhel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/09/20/red-hat-insights-a-predictive-analytics-engine-in-rhel/</guid>
      <description>Something Engineering has been working hard on over the past couple of years is connecting Red Hat’s wealth of internal knowledge with items and issues customers face in the real world everyday. Born out of this effort was Red Hat Insights, a predictive analytics engine that analyzes, assesses, and builds automation to remediate issues found in customer environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating custom credentials in Ansible Tower</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/creating-custom-credentials-in-ansible-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 22:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/creating-custom-credentials-in-ansible-tower/</guid>
      <description>As we go further in our efforts to automate all the things with ansible, you will likely come across a need to manage some cusom credentials that do not come with a predefined type in Ansible Tower. You might be currently setting these in an environment variable, in group_vars or host_vars, or perhaps hardcoded into a playbook itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding python virtual environments (venvs) to Ansible Tower</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/adding-python-virtual-environments-venvs-to-ansible-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 18:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/07/19/adding-python-virtual-environments-venvs-to-ansible-tower/</guid>
      <description>As you’re developing playbooks you may find that you need to add additional python capability in order to use some modules. These are easy enough to install on a regular linux client with pip, but how does this work for Ansible Tower? Fortunately this is not too different for Ansible Tower, we’re just going to instruct Tower to add another source directory for our new venvs, and then assign these in Tower at an Organization, Project, or Job Template level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limiting Ansible Tower inventory with Satellite host groups</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/06/13/limiting-ansible-tower-inventory-with-satellite-host-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 15:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/06/13/limiting-ansible-tower-inventory-with-satellite-host-groups/</guid>
      <description>When thinking about ingesting systems into Ansible Tower’s inventory, a common use-case is to intelligently filter hosts into Ansible Tower such that we’re selectively adding only the hosts we want into Tower inventory. When pairing with Red Hat Satellite, we can use Satellite’s host grouping feature combined with Ansible Tower’s Satellite 6 dynamic inventory script to apply this filtering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Ansible Tower to Team Foundation Server</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/06/connecting-ansible-tower-to-team-foundation-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 18:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/05/06/connecting-ansible-tower-to-team-foundation-server/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was investigating how to connect Ansible Tower to Microsoft Team Foundation Server to source a git repo. To document this for later, I discovered that the way to do this is with an SSH key, and by turning on the SSH service on TFS. Here’s how I got it working:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Workshop Materials</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/02/28/ansible-workshop-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/02/28/ansible-workshop-materials/</guid>
      <description>Recently we had one of the largest and most interesting meetups I think the Calgary market has seen in quite a while. We were able to run an Ansible Workshop, which is a mix of presentation and hands-on lab content. What makes these workshops different (and a reason people love them) is we get to teach a concept, then implement it in a lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Azure VM with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/01/03/create-azure-vm-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2019/01/03/create-azure-vm-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>With a little googling this task isn’t very complex, however, for those wanting to consume this information easily – this post is for you.
There’s a lot of cloud provisioning tools out there; if you’re like me and prefer to leverage your existing knowledge wherever possible you might come to the conclusion that using the same tool to provision your VMs as you do to manage them makes sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible at the Calgary RHUG</title>
      <link>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/15/ansible-at-the-calgary-rhug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://calgaryrhce.ca/blog/2016/09/15/ansible-at-the-calgary-rhug/</guid>
      <description>Today we had a great presentation from Greg Dekoenigsberg, the Director of Global Open Source Community Relations at Ansible (by Red Hat). With configuration management being such a top topic lately, that sentiment sure was reinforced with the number of attendees we had today – we filled the room! Greg gave the group a high-level overview of Ansible’s feature set, along with what the open source community has been seeing for use-cases, and adoption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
